(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Dec. 29, 2021 Japan Tokyo
Watame Tsunomaki 2nd Anniversary Live Fever!!
「美味しいご飯も、可愛いお洋服も要らない。」
"I don't need delicious meals or cute clothes."
「歌が欲しい。全部歌にしてお返ししたい。」
"I want songs. I want to return everything in song."
「わたしは、」
"I..."
「歌いたくてホロライブに来たんだよ。」
"came to Hololive because I wanted to sing."
足跡を残そう。
Let's leave our footprints.
私が生きた証を。
The proof that I lived.
みんなと一緒に歩いた軌跡を。
The path I've walked together with everyone.
I walk slowly, but I never walk backward.
mayday, mayday
メーデー 声は届いてる？ 心がズキッと痛いみたい
Mayday, is my voice reaching you? My heart seems to ache sharply.
ベイベー なんて魅力的 見せるテクニックはすぐにクラクラ
Baby, how charming. Those techniques you show soon make me dizzy.
メーデー それじゃ物足りない すぐにもっともっと欲張りな
Mayday, that's not enough. Soon, I'll be more and more greedy.
ヘイヘイ もっと焦らしてよ あなたの心に入ってたいの
Hey hey, tease me more. I want to be in your heart.
嗚呼 見えすぎた甘い罠
Ah, the sweet trap that's all too visible.
嗚呼 嵌まってあげようか
Ah, shall I fall for it?
嗚呼 自在にコントロールしていたはずなのに
Ah, even though I was supposed to be in full control...
クラ クラしちゃいそうなマインド
A mind that's about to go dizzy.
mayday,mayday
まに合わせをそっと上まで
Just making it work for now.
フラフラ酔い回っちゃうわ
I'm wobbling and feeling dizzy.
ああ もう help me
Ah, help me already.
抜かした負けじゃなくて
It's not a defeat I admitted.
フレフレ ガチの日は何でも
Go for it! Anything on serious days.
君の前じゃ絶対
In front of you, I'm definitely...
help me して
...asking for help.
ねぇ なぜ舵が取れないの
Hey, why can't I steer?
気持ちがモヤっと派手な意志
My feelings are hazy, with a bold will.
メイデイなんかじゃいられない
I can't stay in 'Mayday' forever.
イマドキの子が ワン・モア
Today's girl says, 'One more.'
ちゃめちゃめちゃめちゃ
Messy, messy, messy, messy!
絶対あるわけないじゃない
There's no way that's possible, right?
絶対 ただの勘違い
It's definitely just a misunderstanding.
脳内 手のひらの上で
Inside my brain, on the palm of a hand,
躍らされている鼓動
my heartbeat is being made to dance.
だってさ
Because, you see...
溶け出しなさいな 今を
go ahead and melt into the 'now.'
耳障りな不快音
A grating, unpleasant noise...
私なんだよ ああ
...is me! Ah.
もう help me
Help me already.
嫌嫌 手遅れじゃない?
No, no, isn't it too late?
私を 困らせて なんかもう
Make me troubled, and somehow...
私から言わせたい
...I want to be the one to say it.
rescue me して
...rescue me.
ねぇ どうして
Hey, why...
愛はいたずらするのだろう
...does love play such tricks?
ねぇ いつか
Hey, will this...
この痛みも 消えるの?
...pain ever disappear?
本能は意外簡単に
Instincts are surprisingly easy...
否定して壊れちゃうけど
...to deny and break.
刻まれる 心は ああ
But the heart that is carved, ah...
気がつけば手を伸ばしちゃって
Before I know it, I'm reaching out.
その動作苦しくて
That action is so painful.
君も手を伸ばしてくれたら
If you could reach out too...
痛い ふとした時に痛いの
It hurts, it hurts at unexpected moments.
落ち着く場所 その手で触れてよ
Touch that peaceful place with your hand.
ほらメイデイ
Look, it's Mayday!
フラフラ酔い回っちゃいそうな
I feel like I'm wobbling and getting dizzy.
まに合わせをそっと上まで
Just making it work for now.
フラフラ酔い回っちゃうわ
I'm wobbling and getting dizzy.
ああ もう save me
Ah, save me already.
help me (help me)
rescue me (rescue me)
save me (save me)
メイデイ (メイデイ)
Mayday (Mayday)
だってさ
Because, you see...
溶け出しなさいな 今を
go ahead and melt into the 'now.'
耳障りな不快音
A grating, unpleasant noise...
溢れ出しちゃったんだ
...has started to overflow.
もう rescue me
Rescue me already.
して
Do it.
さあ いつまでも 誇れ この地で 歌おう
Now, forever be proud and sing in this land.
Everlasting Soul
作詞: hotaru 作曲: Tom-H@ck
Lyrics: hotaru, Composition: Tom-H@ck
胸を打ち 震わせる 感動を 鳴らそう 響け
Let's sound the moving emotions that strike the heart. Resonate!
いつか もし 灯火が 消えて 日が尽きるなら
If one day the flame goes out and the day ends...
歌う 心は死なない
...the singing heart will never die.
すべてが 壊れても
Even if everything breaks...
隠していたの 遥かから
I had been hiding it from long ago.
顔に出すのは 容易いと 凌いでた
I got by, thinking it'd be easy to show it on my face.
運命へ
Toward destiny...
打ち果てた 暴ら屋に
In the ruined, dilapidated house...
吹き荒ぶ 風 悲しみさえも
...the wind blows wild, even with sorrow.
raise...
朝が来たって 降り続く 雨が閉ざす
Even if morning comes, the continuous rain shuts it out.
面影さえも 遮る あの歌
That song that even cuts off memories...
今 動き出す 想いは この地で 歌おう
Now, the feelings that start to move will sing in this land.
僅かでも 幽かでも まだ希望 信じたいから
Because even if it's slight or faint, I still want to believe in hope.
奏で出そう 溢れ出す あの笑顔 取り戻せるなら
Let's start playing. If I can regain that overflowing smile...
私の歌は 止まない
...my song will never stop.
この声が 枯れたって
Even if this voice withers away.
変わり果てても 変わらないものがあると
Even if things change completely, I'm told there are things that never do.
目を閉じ浮かべる あの風景
Closing my eyes, that scenery comes to mind.
未だ共に鳴らせる 心があるなら
If there is still a heart that can resonate together...
何一つ無駄じゃない この歌も この愛も
...then nothing is in vain, not this song, nor this love.
鈍色のカランド どこまでも響かせて
Let the lead-colored carillon ring out everywhere.
今はただ虚しい だけ でも願いを込めて
Even if it's just empty right now, I'll put my wish into it.
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
独奏の詩を 絶やした者が
The one who snuffed out the solo poem...
独走の終幕を 望んだとしても
...even if they desired the end of their solo run.
足跡もない この地で歌おう
Let's sing in this land with no footprints.
ただ強く直向きに まだ希望 信じてるから
Just strongly and earnestly, because I still believe in hope.
奏で出し 溢れ出す あの笑顔 取り戻せるなら
If I can take back that smile that starts to play and overflows...
私の歌は止まない この声が枯れるまで
...my song will not stop until this voice withers away.
滅びたこの街で
In this ruined city...
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
For the Everlasting Soul
ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためです！
Hololive 4th generation, Tsunomaki Watame here!
やあ、みんな！聴いてくれてありがとうございます！
Hey everyone! Thank you for listening!
え、今回ね、歌わせていただいた「Mayday, Mayday」と「Everlasting Soul」は...
Uh, the songs I sang this time, "Mayday, Mayday" and "Everlasting Soul"...
この衣装で歌ったことがね、なかったので...
...since I'd never sung them in this outfit before...
選曲させてもらったんですけど、どうだったかな？
...I chose them for the setlist. How was it?
どうだった？どうだった？良かった？
How was it? How was it? Was it good?
かっこよかった？
Was it cool?
頑張ったで！ありがとう！
I did my best! Thank you!
こうして2周年をね、迎えられるのも本当に...
Being able to reach my 2nd anniversary like this is really...
応援してくれてるみんなのおかげだと思っています。
...all thanks to everyone who supports me.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so very much!
ほな、見る？わためのこの衣装。
Now then, want to see? This outfit of Watame's.
見る？見たことない人もいると思うんだけど...
Want to see? I think some people haven't seen it yet...
見る、見る、見る、見る、見る、見る...
Look, look, look, look, look, look...
うおー。リボンがついてたり...
Whoa. It has ribbons on it...
うおー。腰には、羊、わためぇとがついてたり...
Whoa. On the waist, there's a sheep, a Watamate...
うおー、あ、へそも！あ、シースルーでへそが、へそが...
Whoa, oh, the belly button too! Oh, it's see-through and the belly button, the belly button...
そして、バインバインのお胸だったり！
And then, my bouncy chest!
髪型もね、ちょっと違うんですけど...
The hairstyle is a bit different too...
あとはね、爪とかも...おっ、おっ！
And also, the nails... oh, oh!
赤いのが塗ってあったり、こっちは手袋なんだけど...
They're painted red, and this side is a glove, but...
塗ってあったりします。
...they're painted.
あ、あとね、今日のハッシュタグがありまして...
Oh, and also, there's a hashtag for today...
こっちかな？
Is it this way?
ててーん！「#角巻わため2周年ライブ」でぜひたくさんツイートしていただけたら嬉しいです！
Tada! "#TsunomakiWatame2ndAnniversaryLive" - I'd be happy if you tweeted using it a lot!
いっぱいスクショとかね、撮ってください！
Please take lots of screenshots and such!
よろしくお願いします！
I'm counting on you!
えー、そして、この次にね、披露させていただく曲なんですけども...
And then, regarding the next song I'll be performing...
まだ、まだみんなの前で見せたことがない振り付けだったり...
...it's choreography that I haven't shown everyone yet...
おお、ということは、ダンスを踊ったり...
Oh, which means, I'll be dancing...
するので、ぜひね、楽しんでいただきたいなと思います！
...so I really hope you enjoy it!
一緒に踊ったり、歌ったり、サイリウム振ったり...
Let's dance, sing, and wave our lightsticks together...
歌ったり...歌ったって言ったか。楽しんでってください！
Singing... I already said singing. Please enjoy it!
では、次の曲聴いてください。「Rainbow」。
Now then, please listen to the next song. "Rainbow."
RAINBOW / 作詞・作曲：DECO*27
RAINBOW / Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
ねえ、おはようの後
Hey, after saying good morning
もう、落ち込んでるの
I'm already feeling down
ああ、やりたいことも
Ah, the things I want to do
怖いからやめにしたい
I want to stop because I'm scared
もうちょっとだけの自分
Just a little more of myself
もう一歩が踏み出せない
I can't take one more step
そういえばオッケーだった
Come to think of it, it was okay
逃げていられた
I could have just run away
でも君が笑って
But if you're smiling
それでもいいと言うんだったら
and telling me that it's okay
恥ずかしいところとか
The embarrassing parts
ダメダメなところとか
The messy parts
見せたくなくなっちゃうでしょ
I'll end up not wanting to show them
どんな時も前を向いて歌っていたい
I want to keep singing and looking forward no matter what
ほら凹んで泣いて辛い時も
Look, even when I'm feeling down, crying, and having a hard time
強がってるけど平気だよ
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine
きっと君のためならできること
Things I can surely do for you
涙を大嫌いにばらまいて
Scattering my tears that I hate so much
弱かった手に虹を呼び出せるよ
I can call out a rainbow to my weak hands
また明日も多分僕次第で
Tomorrow will probably depend on me, too
今日よりも輝いてく
And it'll shine brighter than today
ねえ、おはようの後
Hey, after saying good morning
なんだか気分がいい
I somehow feel good
もう、繰り返しとか
No more repeating
ない、そう思えるよ
Not anymore, I can feel that
意外と怖くないね
It's surprisingly not scary
あくまで個人の感想です
Just a personal opinion, though
秘められた力とか
Hidden powers
見たことがない奇跡とか
Miracles I've never seen before
そんなのも妄想しちゃうかも
I might even start daydreaming about stuff like that
よーいドンで僕は変わる
At the starting signal, I'll change
合図は君に出してほしい
I want you to give me the sign
大冒険する準備なら
If you're ready for a big adventure
ちゃんと君の分までしておいたよ
I've already made preparations for your part as well
どんな時も前を向いて歌っていたい
I want to keep singing and looking forward no matter what
ほら凹んで泣いて辛い時も
Look, even when I'm feeling down, crying, and having a hard time
強がってるけど平気だよ
I'm acting tough, but I'm fine
きっと君のためならできること
Things I can surely do for you
涙を大嫌いにばらまいて
Scattering my tears that I hate so much
弱かった手に虹を呼び出せるよ
I can call out a rainbow to my weak hands
また明日も多分僕次第で
Tomorrow will probably depend on me, too
今日よりも輝いてく
And it'll shine brighter than today
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いやあ、お着替えしてきたよ。
Man, I'm back in my new outfit.
RAINBOW、どうだったかな？
How was "RAINBOW"?
ダンス、ダンス、ダンス、新しいダンスだったんだけど、どうだったかな？
Dance, dance, dance! It was a new dance, but how was it?
よかった？
Was it good?
練習頑張ったんだよー。
I practiced really hard.
お。
Oh.
あれ？なんか、あれ？なんか、
Wait, huh? Something... wait, huh?
誰か、わぴぴ、誰か来そうななんか、予感がする、わぴぴ。
I have a feeling... wapipi... someone's coming, wapipi.
あれ？
Huh?
くんくん、あれ？わための匂いがするぞ？
Sniff, sniff. Huh? I smell Watame.
その声は！
That voice!
来ましたね。
I'm here.
ぼたんちゃん！
Botan-chan!
わためさん。
Watame-san.
なんでしょうか。
What is it?
2周年おめでとうございます。
Happy 2nd anniversary.
ありがとう！おめでとうを言いに来てくれたのか。
Thank you! Did you come to say congratulations?
と、思いましたか？
Is that what you thought?
思いましたよ。
I did.
あら、おめでとうを言いに来たと思いましたか？
Oh, so you thought I came to say congratulations?
おめでとうを言いに来たと思いました。
I thought you came to say congratulations.
あ、本当ですか。
Oh, really?
違うんですか？
Is it different?
うーん。ちょっとね、わための匂いがしたから、あ、なんかやってんのかなと思って。
Hmm. Well, I smelled Watame, so I thought, "Oh, is she doing something?"
で、まあ、なんかやってるんだったら、まあちょっと乗っ取っちゃおうかなー。
And, well, if she is doing something, I thought I'd just take over for a bit.
乗っ取る！？
Take over!?
え、乗っ取る！？
What, take over!?
あ、なんか画面の前の皆さん、どうも獅白ぼたんです。
Oh, hello everyone watching. I'm Shishiro Botan.
ほらほらほらほら！
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
違いまーす！
No, no!
今日はね、わための番組に...
Today, on Watame's program...
えー、のっとりに来たの？
Eh, did you come to take over?
また今度やればいいじゃん。
You can just do it again next time.
また今度やればいいじゃんって…えー！
"You can do it again next time"... what?!
おかしい、おかしい、おかしい！
That's weird, weird, weird!
えー、だめなの？
Eh, is that not okay?
じゃあ、じゃあ…
Then, then...
じゃあ百歩千歩一万歩譲って…
Then, I'll compromise a hundred, a thousand, ten thousand steps...
お、譲ってくれるの？
Oh, you'll compromise?
うん、譲って…
Yeah, compromise...
なんか勝負で、わために勝てたらいい！
If you can beat Watame in some kind of match, then it's fine!
皆さん、言質取りますよ、今。
Everyone, I'm holding her to that promise right now.
わために勝ったら、じゃあこれ、獅白ぼたんおめでとう配信になるってことですね？
So if I beat Watame, then this becomes a "Congratulations Shishiro Botan" stream?
な、なんなのかな、わかんないけど…
W-what is that, I don't know but...
じゃあちょっと勝負させてくださいよ。
Then please let me challenge you.
ほう、任せろーりん！
Ho, leave it to me!
本当にいいのかい？
Is it really okay?
じゃあ勝負会場とか、準備して…
Then, let's prepare a match venue...
あ、わため道場？
Ah, Watame Dojo?
おお、わため道場。あの看板を奪ったわため道場かい？
Oh, Watame Dojo. The Watame Dojo that stole that signboard?
つのまき道場があるから。
There's the Tsunomaki Dojo.
5期生のみんなでジャンケンをしに行って…
I went to play rock-paper-scissors with everyone in Gen 5...
全員勝って…
Beat everyone...
ネコラムジャンケン…あたま、あたま、ネコラムジャンケン…
Nekoram Rock-Paper-Scissors... my head, my head, Nekoram Rock-Paper-Scissors...
ああたまが…
Ah, my head...
またちょっと看板取りに行っちゃおうかな。
Maybe I'll go take that signboard again.
やっぱ勝負といえばあそこだから。
When it comes to a match, it has to be there.
そうだね。じゃあ一緒に行こうか。
True. Then let's go together.
いいよ。
Okay.
行くよ？
Ready?
いいよ。
Okay.
ジャンプできる？
Can you jump?
じゃ、ジャンプしようか。
Then, let's jump.
せーので行くよ。せーの！
Let's go on three. One, two!
どん！
Jump!
今日はこれで勝負したいと思います！
Today, I want to compete with this!
これだあああ！
This is it!
なにこれ？
What's this?
1-2-Switchだよ！
It's 1-2-Switch!
ゲーム？ゲームよね。
A game? It's a game, right?
そうだよ、ゲームだよ。じゃあこれで勝負して…
Yeah, it's a game. Let's use this for the match...
え、なに、勝ったらなんかあんの？
Eh, what, do I get something if I win?
勝ったらじゃあ、負けたほうが言うことを聞きます！
If you win, the loser will do whatever the winner says!
いいの？そんなこと言っちゃって。
Is that okay? Saying something like that.
記念配信が獅白ぼたんの記念配信になる可能性が、あるけどいいってことね？
There's a chance this anniversary stream becomes Shishiro Botan's anniversary stream, but you're saying that's fine?
え、乗っ取られるの？
Eh, it'll be taken over?
いいよ。
Nice.
大丈夫。勝つから大丈夫だよ。
It's okay. I'll win, so it's okay.
よーし、頑張ろう。勝とう。
Alright, let's do our best. Let's win.
じゃあ、一緒に…
Then, together...
バトルだあああ！
Battle!
禅やるっか。
Let's do Zen.
ええ、禅やるの？何これ、禅って何？何すんの？
Eh, Zen? What's this? What's Zen? What do we do?
わかんない。
I don't know.
精神の強さどっちが強いか。
Let's see whose mental strength is stronger.
羊が勝つ！
The sheep wins!
お、片足だよ。
Oh, on one leg.
これつらそう。
This looks tough.
片足で立ってよ。
Stand on one leg.
これつらーい。
This is tough.
見つめ合うのじゃ！
Stare at each other!
あ！まだいけんじゃない？
Ah! Can't I still go?
ダメかー。
No good?
熱い、熱い！
Hot, hot!
焼かれちゃうよ！
You're gonna get roasted!
ちょっと焦げる、焦げる…燻されちゃう！
I'm burning a bit... I'm getting smoked!
最後ちょっとでも良い匂いしてたよ、わため。燻されて。
You smelled a bit good at the end, Watame. Being smoked.
良い匂いしてた？え、ちょっと煙たくなーい？
Did I smell good? Eh, isn't it a bit smoky?
良い感じにちょっとローストされてたんじゃない？
Weren't you roasted just right?
え、燻製？
Eh, smoked meat?
燻された感想後で聞かせてよ。
Tell me how being smoked felt later.
これはボクシング・ジム！
This is Boxing Gym!
じゃ、やるっか。
Then, let's do it.
アッパーつええ！
Upper is strong!
お、いいよいいよ。
Oh, nice, nice.
オラアアア！
Oraaa!
うっしゃあ！
Usshaa!
良い脇パイです！
Good armpit pie!
でも惜しい！惜しい！
But close! Close!
1点差かー。
One point difference, huh.
1点差だね。
One point difference.
まあね、普段は肉相手に殴ってたからな。
Well, I usually punch meat.
こわ！
Scary!
読めるか？
Can you read it?
真剣白刃取り。ああ、真剣！
Samurai Duel. Ah, serious!
やったことある？
Have you ever done it?
ないよ！
No!
逆に聞きたい、あんのか？
I want to ask you back, have you?
見たこともない。
Never even seen it.
ライオンって…
Lion...
美味しいのかな？
I wonder if they taste good?
くっそー！
Damn it!
さあ、じゃあどうしようかな。
Now, what should I do?
いつでも…
Anytime...
かかってこい。
Come at me.
そうか。何のタレが好き？
I see. What kind of sauce do you like?
何のタレ？
What kind of sauce?
イエーイ！イエーイ！イエーイ！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
ちなみになんのタレが好きだい？
By the way, what kind of sauce do you like?
やっぱ焼肉のタレかな
I guess it's Yakiniku sauce after all.
ぼたんちゃんなんだい？
Botan-chan, what's up?
ランウェイ歩きたくない？
Don't you want to walk the runway?
わためがじゃあランウェイ歩くの？
So, Watame, are you going to walk the runway?
一緒に歩くよ
We'll walk together.
え、すごい
Oh, wow.
あれ...スタイルいいな？
Wait... her proportions are good?
もうランウェイやる前からちょっと
Even before the runway, I'm a bit...
相手を見て！
Look at your opponent!
みんなを見て！
Look at everyone!
どうかな？
How was it?
どう？
How?
わかんないー
I don't know!
イエーイ！
Yay!
やっぱり...
As I thought...
やっぱりプロポーションの違いで...
As I thought, the difference in proportions...
この字が読めなかった...
I couldn't read these characters...
エアギターと見えましたが
It looks like it says "Air Guitar".
初心者だけどやっていいかな？
I'm a beginner, but is it okay if I try?
まあね。今日は、ほら。サングラスつけてきたよ。
Well, you see. Today, look. I brought sunglasses.
かっこいいだろ！
Cool, right!
このサングラスがあればなんか上手く弾ける気がする
With these sunglasses, I feel like I can play well.
確かに！
True!
やるか、じゃあ
Shall we do it, then?
できそうな気がしてきた！
I feel like I can do it!
やるぞ！
Let's do it!
行こうぜ！
Let's go!
自由に行こうぜ！
Let's go wild!
イエーイ！すげー！
Yay! Amazing!
刻んでるぜー！
You're shredding!
刻んでる！
I'm shredding!
弾けよ！
Play it!
弾いてるぜー！
I'm playing!
弾けよ！
Play it!
音楽を聴かないとな
Got to listen to the music.
なるほど！
I see!
イエーイ！
Yay!
こんなんやってたからだよ
It's because you were doing this.
弾いてねーもん
I wasn't even playing.
遊んでた
You were just playing around.
え、ダメなのか
Eh, is that not allowed?
観客の盛り上がりはお互い良かったと思うよ
I think the audience energy was good for both of us.
まあ、勝ちだけどな
Well, I won though.
こんなことしたから...こんなこと...
Because I did this... this...
止めときゃよかった
I should have stopped.
勝てないんだけど...
I just can't win...
全然勝てなくないっすかー？
Don't I ever win?
なんなんすかー？全然勝てなくないっすかー？
What's going on? Don't I ever win?
ちょっと最後5億ポイントぐらい入るのやりません？
Can we do one last game worth about 500 million points?
え、いいの？
Eh, is that okay?
いいよ！
It's okay!
しょうがないな。いいの？
Can't be helped then. You sure?
じゃあ最後に勝った方の言うことを聞こう
Then finally, let's do whatever the winner says.
一発逆転のチャンス！？
A once-in-a-lifetime chance for a turnaround?!
まあまあ反射神経はね
Well, well, as for reflexes...
ライオンから逃げてるからね
I've been running away from a lion, you know.
あ、確かに。足は速いもんな
Ah, true. You are fast on your feet.
勝っちゃうな
I'm going to win.
本当に！あ、勝っちゃう、勝っちゃう
Really! Ah, I'm gonna win, I'm gonna win.
このままだと私5億何ポイントもらうことになるけど
At this rate, I'll be the one getting over 500 million points.
え？
Eh?
そんなんね、なるわけないよなぁ
There's no way that's gonna happen.
相手の目を見ろ！
Look into your opponent's eyes!
猫に見とれてたよ
I was mesmerized by the cat.
どうかな？
How was it?
5億ポイントゲット...！？
500 million points get...!?
5億、おめでとう
500 million, congratulations.
ありがとう！じゃあわたための...
Thank you! Then, for Watame...
次勝った方、6億ポイントにしよう
Let's make the next one worth 600 million points.
6億！？
600 million!?
まあまあ、5億より多いしな
Well, well, it's more than 500 million.
で、言うことを聞こう
And then we'll do what the winner says.
なるほど！
I see!
もっと貰えるならいっか！
If I can get more, then I guess it's fine!
わためこれ勝ったら11億ポイントだからね
Watame, if you win this, you'll have 1.1 billion points.
すげー！すげーよ！
Amazing! That's amazing!
たんまり、たんまり♪
Lots and lots♪
怖いねー
Scary, isn't it.
folkで惑わしてきた！
I confused you with folk!
ツンツンしてやったぜ
I poked you.
folkで惑わしてきたよ
I confused you with folk.
folkでツンツンしてやったぜ
I poked you with folk.
え、えっ、てことは... 6億ポイントはわため？
Eh, so... 600 million points for Watame?
違うよ！わためは5億ポイントで...
No! Watame has 500 million points...
獅白が6億ポイントだから
...and Shishiro has 600 million points, so...
勝者！獅白ぼたん！
Winner! Shishiro Botan!
えええええええ
Eeeeeeeh
でも、まあ... いっぱい負けたからね
But, well... I lost a lot.
しょうがない...
It can't be helped...
いいよ、またじゃあ今度ちょっと、遊ぼうぜ
It's okay, let's play again sometime.
遊ぼうよまた！
Let's play again!
なに言う事聞いてもらおっかな
Now, what should I ask you to do?
せっかくだし、私のさ、オリ曲をさ...
Since we're here, my original song...
一緒に歌ってもらうとかどうです？
...how about singing it with me?
お！え、歌いたいと思ってた！え、いいの？
Oh! Eh, I wanted to sing it! Is it okay?
いいよ。それだったらわためもね、まあ負けても楽しいし
Sure. In that case, Watame will have fun even if she loses.
私も嬉しいし
And I'll be happy too.
優しい！
Kind!
いいんじゃないですかね
Isn't it good?
いいね！
Good!
歌わせていただきます！
I will sing it!
一緒に歌ってください！
Then please sing with me!
お願いします！
Please!
白銀の獅子は
The silver lion
駆けて 駆けて 駆け続けてる
Is running, running, running
もう後ろ振り返ることはないから
Because I'm not looking back anymore
百獣の王は
The king of beasts
自分を信じるから王なんだ
Is king because he believes in himself
We have the pride
Always on fly
それこそ私の誇り
That is my pride
ぽつり ぽつりと 降りだして
Drip by drip, it starts to fall
ずっと 一人なんだろうって 思ってた
I thought I'd be alone forever
前だけ睨んで ただ夢駆けて
Staring ahead, just chasing my dreams
足跡 見失って
Losing track of footsteps
止まらない土煙
Unstoppable dust clouds
倒さない土天
Unyielding earth
はぐれ止まぬ鼓動だって笑った
I laughed even at my straying, unceasing heartbeat
想像のなかった世界 満ちて広がってく
A world beyond imagination fills and expands
人たちの声 野生の声に 翳されて
Shaded by the voices of people and the wild
私は変わりつつある 望みのライオンよ
I am a changing lioness of hope
さあ 手を伸ばし 爪を研ぐ
Now, reach out and sharpen your claws
友の前歩くため
To walk before my friend
真白き獅子は
The pure white lion
触れて 触れて 夢を抱く
Touches and touches, embracing a dream
それが 私を支えてくれるから
Because that is what supports me
純白の心
A pure white heart
覆い 寄り添ってくれるものたち
Those who cover and stay close
We have the pride
Always on fly
それこそ私の誇り
That is my pride
獣だかいフリして 縄張りの
Behaving nobly as a beast, the territory's...
線を 恐怖で無差別に引いていた
...lines were drawn indiscriminately with fear
目指した物だけ 奪い取った物だけ
Only what I aimed for, only what I seized
そしてただ 彷徨うだけ
And then, just wandering
見失う軌道 不安なままでも
Losing track, even while anxious
導き走って 気づいたある日
One day I noticed as I ran guided
溶けなかった孤独に やがて陽が昇る
Finally, the sun rises on the unsolvable loneliness
私たちの根を 少しずつ灯し始めていくから
Because our roots will start to light up little by little
もし永久(とわ)にずっとずっと 離れていても
Even if we are separated forever and ever
理不尽に負け 吼える
Bellowing at the loss to irrationality
友に声届けるため
To reach my voice to a friend
一輪の獅子は
The single lion
咲いて 咲いて 咲き誇りたいのさ
Wants to bloom and bloom proudly
燃え尽きるときは 見守る人のために
When I burn out, let it be for those watching over me
百花の王は
The king of a hundred flowers
一緒に 一緒に 咲き誇りたいのさ
Wants to bloom proudly together
We can be the king of beasts together
はぐれの獅子は
A stray lion
駆けて、駆けて、駆けつけてる
Runs, runs, running towards you
もう、二度と振り返ることはないから
Because I will never look back again
百獣の王は
The king of beasts
究極を信じるからこそさ
Is so because they believe in the ultimate
まだ、まだまだ今日という夢だけを
Still, I can only keep running
見て走っていられる
Towards the dream of today
後ろ見返さず、私達の胸を待つだけの宝
Without looking back, the treasure that waits for our hearts
We have the pride in me always on pride
最高潮、私の誇り
At the climax, my pride
ぼたんちゃん顔見えてへんで。
Botan-chan, your face isn't showing.
あ。
Ah.
見えてへんで。
It wasn't showing.
でもね、
But you know,
うん。
Yeah.
わためと、
With Watame,
うん。
Yeah.
Lioness Prideをまさかね一緒に歌えるとはね。
I never thought I'd be able to sing Lioness Pride together.
ねえ、思ってなかったよ。
Right, I didn't think so either.
いや歌いたかったから嬉しいよー！
No, I really wanted to sing it, so I'm happy!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
な、ちょっとこの歌好きなんだよねーって言うのは噂に聞いてましたよ。
Well, I heard rumors that you liked this song.
歌枠でもね、挑戦したことがあるんだよな。
I've even tried it in my singing streams before.
そうなの？
Is that so?
うん、一緒に歌いたかったんだよー。
Yeah, I wanted to sing it together.
ありがとな。
Thank you.
ありがとう。
今日歌えた。
We sang it today.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
え、でもさ、これ一曲だけ？
Wait, but is it just this one song?
え？
Eh?
一曲で終わっちゃうの？
Does it end with just one song?
まだ歌いたいなあ、一緒に。
I want to sing more, together.
歌いたいよね。
We want to sing more, right?
歌いたいなあ。
I want to sing.
え、でもなんか曲あったっけ？
Eh, but was there another song?
なんか、あるんじゃないんですか？
Isn't there... something?
え、なんかあるんじゃないんですか？
Eh, isn't there something?
知ってんじゃないんですか？
Don't you know?
いやー、なんか噂によると、今日わための配信で、
Well, according to some rumors, in Watame's stream today,
初めて聞ける歌があるとかないとか。
there might or might not be a song that can be heard for the first time.
お、あるとかないとか。
Oh, might or might not.
あるんです！
There is!
えー！
Eh-!
聞きたいなあ。
I want to hear it.
ねえ、みんな知らないのかな？
Hey, I wonder if everyone knows?
お、知らない、もしかして、みんな知らないらしいよ。
Oh, they don't know, it seems like everyone doesn't know.
知らないのかな？
Do they not know?
どうするどうする？
What should we do, what should we do?
教えてあげるか。
Should we tell them?
そうだな、しゃあなしやで、教えたるわ。
Well, I guess we have no choice, we'll tell them.
しゃあなしやで、教えたるわ。
We have no choice, we'll tell them.
教えてあげようかな。
Maybe I'll tell them.
曲名言っちゃってください。
Please say the song title.
お、いいよ、わための配信やし。わためから聞きたいな。
Oh, sure, it's Watame's stream. I want to hear it from Watame.
さっき巻いてたけどえんか？
I was rushing earlier, is it okay?
いいよ。
It's okay.
ほんじゃあ言うで。
Then I'll say it.
どうぞ。
Go ahead.
なんと、ししわたオリジナル曲、
Actually, a ShishiWata original song,
「ししわたクッキング」がー！
"ShishiWata Cooking" is...!
完成しまして。
Completed.
そう。
Yes.
ねえ、今日はぜひね、今この配信を見ている皆様に。
Hey, today, we definitely want to... all of you watching this stream now.
はい。
Yes.
お聞かせしたいなと思ってね。いち早くねお届けしたいなと思いまして。
I wanted to let you hear it. I wanted to deliver it to you as soon as possible.
そうね。
That's right.
え、じゃあどうする？
Eh, so what should we do?
お？どうする？
Oh? What should we do?
ここで歌うの？
Are we singing here?
あ、ここじゃないほうがいいな。
Ah, maybe not here.
あ、そう？
Ah, really?
クッキングだからね。
Because it's cooking.
あ、そうだよね。ししわたクッキングだからなんかちょっとちゃんと調理できそうな。
Ah, that's right. It's ShishiWata Cooking, so maybe somewhere we can actually cook.
ねえ。
Right.
ちゃんとね、装備も整えて。
We need to get our equipment ready too.
いる装備？
Do we need equipment?
いるいるいる！
Yes, yes, yes!
じゃあナイフ持っていくね。
Then I'll bring a knife.
あ、ナイフ。あ、ちょっと危ないね。
Ah, a knife. Oh, that's a bit dangerous.
危ない危ない。あ、あの、なんかフォークっぽいの持っていくわ。
Dangerous, dangerous. Ah, well, I'll bring something like a fork then.
それも危ないけどね！
That's also dangerous though!
それも危ないけど。
That's also dangerous.
まあ移動しますか？
Well, shall we move?
そうね、移動しましょうじゃあ。
Right, let's move then.
はい。
Yes.
移動ー！
Moving!
皆様、ごきげんよう。
Good day to you all.
麺屋ぼたん調理学校、講師のエリザベスししろです。
I am Elizabeth Shishiro, an instructor at Menya Botan Cooking School.
弟子の、メリーわためです。
And I'm the apprentice, Mary Watame.
早速お料理のお勉強、始めていきましょうかわためさん。
Shall we start our cooking lessons right away, Watame-san?
はい、先生！
Yes, teacher!
ししわたクッキング
ShishiWata Cooking
作詞：まろん (IOSYS) 作曲・編曲：REDALiCE
Lyrics: Maron (IOSYS) / Composition & Arrangement: REDALiCE
まずは卵ポイと入れて
First, pop in an egg
ポイポイ
Pop pop
トントントン、腕を振るいましょう
Tonton-ton, let's show off our skills
あっちゃっちゃ、火傷にご用心
Ouch-ouch, watch out for burns
楽しくお料理
Cooking is fun
先生、次は何をすればいいですか？
Teacher, what should I do next?
料理とエイムはですね、コツがいるんですよ。
Cooking and aiming require a certain knack.
なるほど。
I see.
混ぜよ　ふわふわのドリル
Mix it up, fluffy drill
トップ製ソースを作りましょう
Let's make some top-grade sauce
トプスソー　つければわかる　素敵なオリオリ
Top-grade sauce—you'll know when you taste it, a wonderful creation
さてさて、今日のメインの料理
Now then, today's main dish is
コンソメ風味のジンギスカン
Consomme-flavored Jingisukan (grilled lamb)
生なまゆでておりますけれども　Let's go Kitchen!
It's being boiled raw, though—Let's go, Kitchen!
何てやり取りも冗談だね
That kind of exchange is just a joke
隠し味だから、冗談ですよ
It's a secret flavor, so it's a joke
先輩、さあどうぞ　テーブルへご案内
Senpai, here you go, let me guide you to the table
とっておきの愛情込めて　美味しくなーれ
With extra special love, become delicious
エプロンつけてお料理するよ　おいで　おいで　こっちこっち
Putting on an apron and cooking, come here, come here, this way, this way
一緒に食べればハッピー　溢れるね
If we eat together, we'll be happy and it'll overflow
そんな時間と　こんな笑顔が　大好きししわたクッキング
I love that time and this smile, Shishi Wata Cooking
説明しよう！ししろフード調理学校とは
Let me explain! The Shishiro Food Cooking School is...
えーと、美味しいラム肉料理を研究する…
Uh... a place to research delicious lamb dishes...
ねぼたちゃん、これ合ってる？
Nebota-chan, is this right?
合ってるよー
It's right!
あ、食材がない
Oh, we're out of ingredients.
そして、新たな食材を探しに、サバンナの奥地へとやってきたのであった。
And so, they traveled deep into the savanna to find new ingredients.
並べ　極上サンダイ和牛
Line up the premium Sandai Wagyu
情け容赦サバイバル
Merciless survival
ドトード　肉体限界　ガンガン極めてこう
Doto-do, physical limits, let's keep pushing hard
仕留めはバッチリと任せてくださいよ
Leave the final blow perfectly to me
何とかしてくれる、ししろボタン
She'll handle it, Shishiro Botan
この世は丸三角四角　弱肉強食　ひえー
The world is circles, triangles, and squares; survival of the fittest—yikes!
もうだめ　腹ペコ　さあさあ早く食べよう
I'm spent and starving, come on, let's eat quickly
太陽の下イグニッションさ　楽しいよね
Ignition under the sun—it's fun, isn't it?
彩りどりの　お弁当箱へ　詰めよう　詰めよう　ときめき
Into the colorful lunch box, let's pack, let's pack the excitement
目と目合わせてハッピー　召し上がれ
Eye to eye, we're happy—enjoy your meal
そんな時間と　こんな笑顔が　大好きししわたクッキング
I love that time and this smile, Shishi Wata Cooking
Hey yo, 腹減りピープル put your hands up!
Hey yo, hungry people, put your hands up!
紹介する今宵のシチュエーション
Introducing tonight's situation
お肉　待てないライオンガール
The meat-loving lion girl who can't wait
野菜はちょっといいですか？
Can we skip the vegetables?
いやいや、ライム刻んでライム紡ぐスタイルがMy Boom
No, no, slicing lime and spinning rhyme style is my boom
悪くはないよ鉄板ネタ
Not bad for a classic routine
産地直送エンターテイナー
A farm-to-table entertainer
いつか遠い未来で思い出す
Someday in the far-off future, we'll remember
そんな時間を　こんな笑顔を　もっともっと作ろうよ
That time and this smile, let's make more and more of them
とっておきの愛情込めて　美味しくなーれ
With extra special love, become delicious
みんなのために　お料理するよ　おいで　おいで　こっちこっち
Cooking for everyone, come here, come here, this way, this way
一緒に食べればハッピー　溢れるね
If we eat together, we'll be happy and it'll overflow
そんな時間と　こんな笑顔を　毎日お届けする
Bringing you that time and this smile every single day
人気番組ししわたクッキング　グー！
The popular show, Shishi Wata Cooking, Goo!
それでは皆さん、また明日！
Well then everyone, see you tomorrow!
明日の食材は、新鮮なラム肉です。
Tomorrow's ingredient will be fresh lamb.
何て？
Wait, what?
ふぅ、んー、いやぁー
Phew, hmmm, yeah...
楽しかったねー
That was fun!
ということで、わため、この曲は一体何なんだい？
So, Watame, what on earth is this song?
この曲は、ししわたのオリジナルソングです！
This song is a Shishi-Wata original song!
今日、初公開だよね？
It's the first time we've performed it, right?
ね、そうなんですよ、実はね。
Yeah, that's right, actually.
ってことは、なんかこの後動画とか出たり？
Does that mean a video will be released after this or something?
動画とか、お、なんか、あれ、後ろになんか、お、あるけど
A video... oh, wait, what's that behind us?
これさ、お、ちょっと私帽子デカい
Look at this... oh, wait, my hat is huge.
マジでデカい。長い。
It's seriously big. And long.
これさ、洋食料理のさ、洋がさ、すごくない？
About this... isn't the '洋' (Western) in '洋食料理' (Western cuisine) amazing?
あのサンズイのシあるじゃん。シみたいな。
You know the 'shi' radical? It looks like 'shi'.
おいししろのシを取ったら羊食料理になるってこと？
Wait, if you take Shishiro's 'Shi' (シ) out of it, does it become 'Sheep-eating cuisine' (羊食料理)?
そうなんだよなー。洋食料理、おかしいなー、思ってたんと違うなー。
That's how it is. 'Western cuisine'... that's weird, not what I expected.
あ、でもさ、シ取っても、ほら、洋食料理だから
Ah, but even if you take 'shi' out, see, it's still 'Western cuisine' (but written with sheep).
まった、確かに。ししろフードね。
Wait, true. Shishiro Food.
読み方、まあまあ。確かに。
The reading is... well, true enough.
クッキングスタジオにね、洋食料理屋さんにね、ちょっと手広くやっておりますけれども。
In the cooking studio, we're operating as a Western-style restaurant on a broad scale.
ね、助手として入っちゃったよ。
Yeah, I ended up joining as an assistant.
もう逃げられないよ。
You can't escape anymore.
じゃ、このオリジナル曲は、え、いつ、あんなの？来るの？
So, this original song... uh, when is it... coming out?
このね、
Regarding this...
フミ先生にね、イラストを描いていただきまして
Fumi-sensei drew an illustration for me.
このあと、
And after this,
10時！
at 10:00...
おっ
Oh!
15分に！
15 PM!
わためのチャンネルで
On Watame's channel,
投稿いたします！
it will be posted!
イエーイ！ぼたんちゃん、ありがとう！
Yay! Botan-chan, thank you!
楽しみ！
I'm looking forward to it!
Can't wait!
ぜひね、ちょっとね、動画でまたね、
I'd love for everyone to see it
みんなに見ていただけたら嬉しいなと
in the video format.
思いますけれども
I hope you enjoy it.
見てください！
Please watch it!
はい。
Yes.
えっ、これだけ？
Eh, is that all?
え？
Eh?
まさか、まさか！
No way, no way!
おっ？
Oh?
まさかこれだけじゃありません！
That's certainly not all!
ありません！
It is not!
じゃあちょっとわためさん、
Then, Watame-san,
はい。
Yes.
教えてくださいよ。
please tell us more.
実は、
Actually,
角巻わため2周年グッズが
Tsunomaki Watame's 2nd anniversary merchandise
発売に
is going on
なりまして、
sale,
おっ！
Oh!
その中のグッズ、
and among the items,
『わためのうた Vol.2』
"Watame no Uta Vol.2"
アルバムに
is becoming an
なります！
album!
イエーイ！
Yay!
スペシャル・トラックでね、
As a special track,
このししわたクッキングも
this ShishiWata Cooking is also
入ってますのでね。
included in it.
おっ！え、いいの？入れてもらって。
Oh! Is it okay for me to be included?
え、こっちこそいいの？入れて。
Eh, are you sure it's okay for me to add you?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
全11曲だよ！
It's 11 tracks in total!
スペシャル・トラックに。
Including the special track.
うーん。
Yeah.
ねー。
Right.
ありがとね。入れてくれてありがとな。
Thanks. Thank you for including it.
ちょっと、え、
Wait, um,
ちなみに、じゃあ
by the way,
『わためのうた』だけ？
is it just "Watame no Uta"?
え？どういうこと？
Eh? What do you mean?
え、その、出るっていうの。
Eh, like, other things being released.
あ、なるほど！
Ah, I see!
いや、『わためのうた Vol.2』だけじゃないんですよ！
No, it's not just "Watame no Uta Vol.2"!
ないのね！
It's not!
じゃあちょっと聞きたいな、いろいろ。
Then I want to hear about the rest.
おっ！
Oh!
いいんですか、言っても。
Is it okay if I say it?
いいよ。聞かせて、聞かせて。
Go ahead. Let us hear it.
『わためのうた Vol.2』
"Watame no Uta Vol.2"
制作秘話ブックレット、
Production Story Booklet...
出ます！
...is coming out!
おー！
Oh!
イエーイ！わー、かわいい！
Yay! Wow, it's cute!
なんとね、
And you know,
まあ、このアルバムを作るまでに、
well, leading up to making this album,
ソロライブとかいろいろありましてね。
I had my solo live and various other things.
ふむふむ。
I see, I see.
この曲に対するちょっとね、わための気持ち、
I put my feelings about these songs,
お気持ち？
Your feelings?
お気持ち。
My feelings.
お気持ち詰まってる？
Are they packed in there?
お気持ちがね、たくさん詰まっておりますよ！
There are lots of feelings packed into it!
なるほどね。じゃあちょっと見たいな、
I see. Then I want to see
わためのお気持ち。
Watame's feelings.
お気持ちはずかしいな、そう言われるとちょっと見られるの恥ずかしいけど。
It's embarrassing when you say it like that. It's a bit shy to have people see them.
じゃあどんな気持ちでね、その曲歌ったとかさ、
Like, what kind of feelings you had while singing,
いろいろ見れるってことね。
you can see all that.
そうだよ、いろいろね、
That's right, all sorts of things
書き詰まっとる。
are written in there.
ちなみにこれ、フミ先生の描き下ろしじゃん。
By the way, this is a new illustration by Fumi-sensei.
あのCD、
That CD...
CDも見れる？
Can we see the CD too?
見れるよ！
You can!
あ、見れる？
Oh, we can?
CDも見たいなー。
I want to see the CD too.
これはね、ラフ段階のね、
This is an illustration in the rough stages,
イラストなんだけど、
but...
それを表紙にさせていただきまして。
we used it for the cover.
あ、CD！
Ah, the CD!
こちらが、
This is...
CDのジャケットのイラストになります！
...the CD jacket illustration!
かわいいね、空飛んでるね。
It's cute, she's flying in the sky.
ねー。羊もよう空飛んどるで。
Yeah. The sheep is flying well in the sky too.
飛んどるね。
She is flying.
空飛ぶ時代になったんじゃ。
It's the age of flying in the sky now.
へー、すごいな。進化してるな。
Heh, amazing. Evolving, huh.
うーん、そうだよ。
Yeah, that's right.
まだまだ！
There's more!
お、まだある？
Oh, still more?
まだまだ、グッズも進化しますよ！
The merchandise is still evolving!
おっ、聞かせて聞かせて。
Oh, let us hear it.
なんと、
And then,
LEDアクリルスタンドライトも出ます！
the LED acrylic stand light is also coming out!
LED！あ、かわいい！
LED! Ah, it's cute!
かわいいよね！
It is cute, right?
かわいい！
So cute!
何何これ？
What is this?
日本一ソフトウェアさん知ってる？
Do you know Nippon Ichi Software?
あ、知ってる知ってる。流行り神とかやってた。
Ah, I do, I do. They made Hayarigami and stuff.
あー、やってたね。そういえば。
Ah, they did. Come to think of it.
やってたやってた。
They did, they did.
まあその日本一さんの作品の中でも、
Well, among Nippon Ichi's works,
あの『嘘つき姫と盲目王子』とか、
like "The Liar Princess and the Blind Prince",
そういったゲームのイラストを書かれていらっしゃる
the illustrator for those games,
小田沙耶佳先生に描き下ろしていただいたんですよ！
Oda Sayaka-sensei, drew this for me!
え、めっちゃかわいい！ほんわかしてる。
Eh, it's so cute! It has a soft feel.
ねー。
Right.
なんとこれ、下からね、ライトが
Actually, with this, the light from below
ふわーっと当たってね、
shines gently,
へー。
Heh.
おー。
Oh.
弱火？
Low heat?
弱火！
Low heat!
弱火ってこと？
You mean low heat?
弱・火！
Low. Heat!
うん。
Yeah.
LED弱火の火がじゃあ灯されるってことね。
So a "low heat" LED flame will be lit, then.
ま、火は灯さんのだけどな。
Well, it doesn't actually light a fire.
火は灯さんけどね。
No fire, of course.
なるほどね。じゃあ幻想的なわためが見れるってことね。
I see. So we can see a mystical Watame.
そうだね。ねー。
That's right. Yeah.
あったけーわためが見れますよ！
You can see a warm Watame!
あ、楽しみだね。癒やされてください。
Ah, looking forward to it. Please be healed.
はい。
Yes.
まだ、終わらない！
It's not over yet!
あ、まだあるの？
Ah, there's still more?
まだあります！
There is still more!
何何？
What is it?
シチュエーションボイスも出ます！
A situation voice is also coming out!
おっ、どんなやつ？
Oh, what kind?
これは、
This is,
あのソロライブがあったじゃないですか。
about that solo live I had.
あったあった。
Right, right.
その、帰り道ね、
On the way home,
君と二人でみたいな、
just the two of us...
みたいなわための、妄想が、妄想が！
Watame's fantasy, a fantasy!
ジュルリみたいなやつ？
A drooling kind of thing?
そうだね、妄想が、はずかしい！
That's right, the fantasy is so embarrassing!
あはは！え、これわためが書いたの？
Ahaha! Eh, did Watame write this?
そうだよ。
Yes, I did.
シナリオ？
The scenario?
そうだよ。
That's right.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
全部考えて。
I thought up the whole thing.
わー、すごいじゃん！
Wow, that's amazing!
これはぜひちょっと聞きたいね。
I definitely want to hear this.
はずかしい！
It's embarrassing!
どんな気持ちで書いたんだい？
What kind of feelings did you have while writing it?
お気持ち、妄想いっぱい詰まっております！
My feelings and fantasies are fully packed in!
ああ、楽しみだ見たいなお気持ち。
Ah, I'm looking forward to seeing those feelings.
ねー、ちょっと恥ずかしくなってきたな。
Yeah, I'm starting to get a bit shy.
でもこれ、セット販売も
But there's also a set
ありまして、
available for sale,
お、おお。
Oh, oh.
はい。セット販売だと、
Yes. And with the set sale,
はい。
Yes.
あの、まあ箔押しサインにはなっちゃうんですけども、
well, it'll be a foil-stamped signature,
ポストカードがね、付いてきたりとか。
but you'll get a postcard with it.
これはお得ですね。
That's a good deal.
特典ボイスが付いてきたりとかします！
And it comes with an extra bonus voice!
ほうほうほう。
Ho ho ho.
なんと1万円！
It's only 10,000 yen!
よっ、買おう！
Alright, let's buy it!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ちなみにこれは、新しいホロライブショップで販売されると。
By the way, these will be sold at the new Hololive Shop.
そうです！
Yes!
何時から？
From what time?
お！この後、なんと、10時からです！
Oh! After this! From 10 PM!
お、10時からだぞ、みんな。忘れずに。
10 PM, everyone! Don't forget!
単品売りもありますので、よろしくお願いします。
Single items are also available, so please check them out!
楽しみだね。イェイイェイイェイ～
Looking forward to it! Yeah yeah yeah~
そっか。
I see.
ちょっとじゃあ後で買うね、これ。
I'll buy them later.
あげる、あげる！
I'll give them to you! I'll give them to you!
あ、くれるの？
Oh, you'll give them to me?
ありがとう。
Thanks!
で、この後10時15分からししわたクッキングの動画が…
And after that, from 10:15 PM, the Shishiwata Cooking video...
そう、上がります！
...will be uploaded!
10時と10時15分もチェックしてください。
So check both 10:00 PM and 10:15 PM, please!
ください！
Please!
さて、そんなこんなで。
Now then...
あの、わためさん、この後何か注文入ってるんですか？
Watame-san, do you have any orders next?
いや実はね、My songの注文が入ってるんですよね。
Well actually, I have an order for 'My song'.
My songといえば。
Speaking of 'My song'...
このアルバムの表題曲になっております。
It's the title track of this album.
なるほど。じゃあこの注文はちょっとわためさん一人で頑張ってもらいたいなと思うので…
I see. I'd like you to handle this order on your own, Watame-san...
エリザベス獅白はちょっと次の修行に行ってまいります。
...so Elizabeth Shishiro will go on to her next training.
先生！寂しいけど。
Sensei! It's lonely, but...
助手のわため頑張りたいと思います！
...assistant chef Watame will do her best!
頑張ってな。
Good luck.
ちゃんとしっかり食材は余らすことなく使うんだぞ。
Make sure to use all the ingredients without wasting anything.
食材？しっかりね。
Ingredients? Got it.
弱火でじっくり教わった通りに歌いたいと思います。
I'll 'sing' slowly on low heat just as I was taught.
では、My song聴いてください。
Now, please listen to 'My song'.
手にしたもの以外が綺麗に見えた
Things other than what I had looked beautiful
どうせこんなもんかとちっぽけだった
I thought "Is this all?" and felt small
面白笑いばっかが得意になった
I became good at just putting on a fake smile
けど一番笑えんのはこのプライドだ
But what's least funny is this pride
一生懸命なんか全部無駄だったんだ
All my hard work was all in vain
ああもう嫌になった
Ah, I'm sick of it all
「逃げたくない」って聞こえた　これは僕の声
"I don't want to run away," I heard. It's my own voice.
1回 10回 100回 1000回　挑戦を続けるよ
1 time, 10 times, 100 times, 1000 times, I'll keep on challenging
まだ足りないって思ってる　やまない雨の中
I still don't think it's enough, in the unending rain
ずっと考えて考えて考えて見つけ出せ
Keep thinking, thinking, thinking, and find it
僕だけの滑走路を証明したいんだよな
I want to prove my own runway, don't I?
そうだろう？
Isn't that right?
競り上がる心拍数　理屈を飲み
Rising heart rate, swallowing down logic
自分を落ち着ける　皮肉は要らない
Calming myself down, I don't need any irony
それも高揚感に置き換えたらさ
If I replace that with excitement too
今日もまた挑むべきハードルだ　ほら見えただろ
It's another hurdle to take on today. Look, you can see it now.
葛藤の隙間で錆びない生命をひねり出せるか
In the gaps of conflict, can I wring out a life that doesn't rust?
出ないのならとっくに諦めてるよ
If it wasn't coming out, I would have given up long ago
渾身の信念で歌ったって届くわけじゃない
Even singing with my whole heart doesn't mean it'll reach
素晴らしい甲斐　僕らの現実は残酷だ
A wonderful worth, our reality is cruel
曖昧を削り取って尖らせてまた歌って
Scraping away the ambiguity, sharpening it and singing again
諦める理由なら過去に捨ててきた
I threw away the reasons for giving up in the past
愛してたいよ
I want to keep loving
立ち止まる度に　進みたがる足を　まだ行こう
Every time I stop, my feet want to move forward. Let's go further.
もっと行こう
Let's go even further
小さくて頼りなくて不安定な歩幅が
Small, unreliable, and unstable strides
繋がって歌になる　僕を聞いてくれ
Connect and become a song. Please listen to me.
1回 10回 100回 1000回　挑戦を続けるよ
1 time, 10 times, 100 times, 1000 times, I'll keep on challenging
まだ足りないって思ってる　やまない雨の中
I still don't think it's enough, in the unending rain
ずっと考えて考えて考えて見つけ出せ
Keep thinking, thinking, thinking, and find it
僕だけの栄光を証明したいんだよな
I want to prove my own glory, don't I?
もし辿り着いたなら　誇っていいかな
If I finally arrive, can I be proud?
みんなー！
Everyone!
マイソング聴いてくれてありがとー！
Thank you for listening to My Song!
心を込めて、えー、歌わせていただきました。
I sang it, uh, with all my heart.
力みすぎちゃったよー！
I put too much effort into it!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
今「My song」のね、えー、動画も鋭意制作中なので、お待ちください。
A music video for "My Song" is currently in production, so please look forward to it.
あと、あの、グッズなんですけど、ちょっとね、追加で言いたいこともあるので...
Also, about the goods, there's something more I'd like to say...
もう一回説明してもいいですか？
May I explain them one more time?
いい？大丈夫？
Is that okay? Is it alright?
じゃあもう一回、お願いしまーす！
Then, once more, please!
どどん！
Dodon!
角巻わため、活動2周年記念、このあと10時発売になります！
Tsunomaki Watame's 2nd anniversary commemorative goods will go on sale after this at 10 PM!
イエーイ！
Yay!
え、細かいとこも見ていくと...お？
Let's take a closer look at the details... Oh?
なんと、えー、角巻わため、「わためのうた」Vol. 2、セカンドアルバムが出ます！
Surprise, Tsunomaki Watame's "Watame no Uta" Vol. 2, my second album, is coming out!
ありがとう、みんなのおかげでセカンドアルバムがね、出せることになりました。
Thank you, thanks to everyone, I'm able to release a second album.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
え、セトリがね、あの、ソロライブでも、あの、披露させていただいた曲＋、
The tracklist includes songs I performed at my solo live, plus,
え、ししわたクッキングがね、ボーナストラックで入りまして...
uh, "Shishiwata Cooking" as a bonus track...
え、このね、順番とかも自分で考えたんですよ。
And I thought of the song order myself!
「これ、こっちにこうしようかな」とか、「この曲はあとにしようかな」とか、
"Maybe I should move this here," or "Maybe this song should come later,"
考えたので、ぜひ聴いてほしいなと思います。
I thought about it, so I really want you to listen to it.
で、ジャケットイラストはふーみママが描いてくださっているんですけど...
The jacket illustration was drawn by Fuumi-mama, but...
けど、なんとこちらね、あの、アルバムとしてもぜひ買ってもらいたいんだけど...
But, while I'd love for you to buy it as an album...
え、このあと24時からサブスク配信もあります！
it will also be available on streaming services starting at midnight!
イエーイ！
Yay!
え、なので、あの、アルバムとしてね、えー、お手元とか、あとはなんかお部屋に置いたりとか、
So, for those who want the physical album to keep, or to display in your room,
あとは聴くのにね、保存用とか、聴く用とか、あの、配布用とかね、買いたい人はグッズで買ってもらって...
or to have as a collection, to listen to, or to give away, please buy the goods...
んで、え、音源だけでいいかなって方はあの、サブスクの方でも聴けますので、
And for those who just want the music, you can listen on streaming services,
ね、24時からぜひチェックしてください。
so please check it out starting at midnight.
え、そして...
And next...
おっ、わためのうたVol. 2、制作秘話ブックレットが出ます！
Oh, the "Watame no Uta Vol. 2" Production Story Booklet is coming!
なんとA4判16ページ。多いね！
It's A4 size and 16 pages long. That's a lot!
これわためもね、あの、つらつらと、あの、曲に対するね、思いとかなんかこういう気持ちで歌ったよーとか、
In this, I'll be writing down my thoughts on the songs, the feelings I had while singing,
なんか詞を書いたよーとか、そういうのをね、書き連ねたいと思いますので...
how I wrote the lyrics, and things like that...
よかったら手に取って読んでみてほしいなと思います。
So if you'd like, I hope you'll pick it up and read it.
そして...
And...
LEDアクリルスタンドライト！
The LED Acrylic Stand Light!
えー、これは今ね、あの、「悪い王様と立派な勇者」っていう日本一ソフトウェアさんのゲームやらせてもらってるんですけど...
Currently, I'm playing a game by Nippon Ichi Software called "The Cruel King and the Great Hero"...
え、そのキャラクターデザインだったり、ま、背景とかイラスト全般を担当されている小田沙耶佳先生にお願いをしまして...
And I asked Sayaka Oda-sensei, who is in charge of character designs and illustrations for that game...
え、なんと、わためのオリ曲「Holidays!」をね、イメージして描いていただいたんですよ。
to draw this with the image of my original song, "Holidays!"
だから、猫とか、あの、鳥とか、花とか、歌詞に出てくるんだけど...
So, things like cats, birds, and flowers that appear in the lyrics...
え、それをね、表現していただきました。
She expressed those for me.
下からね、あったかい、ほわーっとした光がね、こう漏れてくるのでね、漏れてくる...
A warm, soft light glows from underneath... "glows"...
綺麗になりますのでね、よかったら、あの、おうちに置いてほしいなと思います。
It looks very pretty, so I hope you'll display it at home.
そして...
And...
おっ、これフルセット全部ですね、購入していただいた方には、箔押しになっちゃうんだけど、サイン入りポストカード＋...
Oh, for those who purchase the full set, you'll get a postcard with a foil-stamped signature, plus...
あとは特典ボイスが聴けます！
a bonus voice!
フルセット購入した人しか聴けない特典ボイスがついてくるので、えー、ぜひ聴いてほしいなと思います。
It comes with a bonus voice that only full-set purchasers can hear, so I really want you to listen to it.
あとは...
Also...
あの、特典じゃないんだけど、あの、さっきも言ったんだけどね、記念ボイス、あの、ソロライブのあと、君と二人で...
Um, this isn't a bonus, but like I said before, there's a commemorative voice pack,
みたいな自分でね、考えた妄想が...
about a fantasy scenario I came up with, like being alone with you...
あの、詰まってるボイスもありますのでね、えー、これもぜひ、あの、聴いてほしいなと思います。
It's filled with that, so I hope you'll listen to this as well.
こんなもんかな？
Is that everything?
はい、なのでこのあと10時からは、あの、グッズをチェックしていただいて、
Yes, so please check out the goods starting at 10 PM,
10時15分はししわたクッキングをチェックしていただいて、
then check out "Shishiwata Cooking" at 10:15 PM,
24時はサブスク配信ありますので、「わためのうた」Vol. 2ぜひゲットしてほしいなと思います。
and with streaming starting at midnight, I hope you'll get "Watame no Uta" Vol. 2.
ここまで、えー、聴いてくれて...んで噛んじゃった。
Thank you for listening this far... and I stumbled over my words.
最後まで見てくれて本当にみんなありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to everyone for watching until the end!
今年はね、ソロライブをさせていただいたりとか、がっつりねライブというものをさせていただいたので、
This year, I had my solo live and did quite a lot of live performances,
今日の2周年はちょっとあの、お遊び入れたりとか、
so for today's 2nd anniversary, I added a bit of playfulness,
あとはゲスト呼ばせていただいて、一緒に歌ってもらったりとかしてもらったんだけど、
and I also invited guests to sing with me and things like that,
楽しんでもらえたかな？
I wonder if you enjoyed it?
いつもドキドキだよ。
I'm always nervous.
今年は本当に、いろいろ忙しいドタバタした1年だったんだけど、
It was a really busy and hectic year this year,
オリ曲ね、10曲プラス、あとはユニットとかで2曲プラス、
but with 10 original songs, plus 2 more from units,
あのししわたクッキングの方もやって13曲ね。
and including ShishiWata Cooking, that's 13 songs.
新しい曲を覚えて歌ったりしたんですけど、
I've been learning and singing new songs,
そういう機会をもらえるのも本当にみんなのおかげだと思っています。ありがとうございました。
and I believe it's all thanks to everyone that I get those opportunities. Thank you very much.
本当に感謝、あの、言っても言っても言っても言っても足りないぐらいなんだけど、本当にありがとうございました。
Truly grateful... I can't say it enough, no matter how many times I say it, but thank you so much.
では。
Well then.
また、3年目もよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to your support in my third year as well.
最後はあのポーズやるぞ！
I'm going to do that pose at the end!
わかる？あのポーズ、わためと言ったらあのポーズ。
Do you know which one? That pose, if you're talking about Watame, it's that pose.
決めますよ、最後に。
I'll do it, one last time.
では。
Now.
わため、ナンバー、ワン！
Watame, Number, One!
またねー！
See ya!
ついに重大発表あります！
Finally, there's a big announcement!